This video just might change your life
and it certainly will affect your
business. There's a concept that I
believe I've been teaching it for a long
time that is so important if you are a
coach or mentor who wants to make more
money online that's going to absolutely
change everything for you. My name is
Jeremiah Kowski and for the last 22
years I've been building online coaching
and course businesses to scale over
eight figures online and I work with
coaches and mentors every single week in
my wealthy coach academy to show them
exactly step by step what to do to be
able to reach those goals for
themselves. The number one thing that I
see that a lot of the best coaches do,
and I'm talking the people that I work
with, they are some of the best that are
out there. they've been mentoring people
for years is they deal with a problem
where their spirit of excellence, their
desire for excellence causes them to not
reach the people that they want to
reach. This is a form of perfectionism
that ends up manifesting in their
business where they want things to be
done well. They want to impact people
well. They want it to be effective. And
really ultimately, it does sometimes
boil down to a form of control. Trying
to control the outcome, trying to
control perceptions of people. Before I
recorded this video, I was dealing with
this myself. And I deal with this often.
And this is something that, listen, I
don't have the answers for in 100% of
the ways, but I know some frameworks
that have gotten me to break past this
in my own business. See, I know the
impact that my programs have with
people. I know the impact that my videos
have. I know that when people take to
heart what I share and they apply it,
the kind of results that they get.
Because of that, I want to make sure
that everybody who watches my content
gets a huge result out of working with
me. Here's the problem though that if I
obsess over the details of making sure
that I am controlling the outcome for
every single person who watches my
YouTube videos, who visits my websites,
who sees my advertising campaigns,
I will literally cause myself to not do
anything, to go into a state of
inaction, overplanning,
trying to curate with excellence
to make everything perfect all of the
things that I am doing in my business
and because there's an internal belief
and sometimes there's a struggle here
where there's a part of me that's like
okay if I get all this right I'm going
to make more money. The truth is though
as I also have backed by 22 years of
experience knowing that actually if I
just show up authentically if I just
connect if I just let if I just press
record on a video that generally the
things that I say are actually going to
be really really good. And this is a
paradigm shift for most people. This is
something that I constantly have to
remind myself of all the time when it
comes to creating content and when it
comes to making my courses and my
programs and my marketing materials,
even when it comes to creating webinars,
when it comes to writing email marketing
campaigns and all the stuff that we have
to do in our coaching business, I still
have to remind myself, you know what?
Done. getting it done, making progress,
recording this video, pressing record,
even if it's not perfect, even if I
don't have the right half second nuance
to what I say or maybe I stutter over my
words a little bit, which by the way,
that's just the most authentic version
of me that you're going to get is that
if I'm talking that way with you, it's
probably the most real that I can be.
I'm not going based off of notes or
curating things. You know, I used to I
used to have notes all the time in front
of me anytime I would make a video. Now
I realize, you know what, those videos
didn't do as well. The ones when I just
showed up authentically to make a
connection with somebody. That's what
actually works the best. And so
cultivating and curating the energy
inside of myself is actually one of the
best things that I do. So here's what I
actually do. This is one of my
strategies. Number one, I will visualize
myself in my mind making a great video,
making a great piece of content. Then I
will start to scroll through different
pieces of content from different
creators. This is a strategy that
sometimes I forget, sometimes I do. What
I will do then is it's going to connect
my energy with those creators that I'm
connecting with their content. And then
from there, what flows out of that is
actually something that's really great.
It only takes about five minutes to do.
And then what flows out of that is
something that's really good. Now, you
might say, "Well, that that's great,
Jeremiah, but like what about what
you're actually going to talk about?"
Okay, let me explain this. What I do is
I pay attention to all of my clients
that I'm working with, the people that I
work with on a daily basis. What do they
want to learn? What do they desire to
learn from me? What are the things that
I can share that they will benefit from?
I take the questions that they ask. What
are the most common questions and what
are the most common struggles that are
keeping them from being successful and
then that gives me ideas for what to
talk about. Now come up with the main
idea and then I will press record. And
so what we got to do is this is we have
to get a bird's eye view for our ideas.
Use artificial intelligence to help you
come up with some of these ideas as
well. I filter a lot of my transcripts
from my sessions with clients into AI to
give me ideas. But then at the end of
the day, we got to learn how to shorten
the amount of time from I have an idea
to taking action. We can talk ourselves
into chronic time wasting where we are
constantly trying to perfect and perfect
and make things a little bit better, a
little bit better, a little bit better,
a little bit better
to the point that we do nothing. And
then we sit around and an hour goes by
and we've still done nothing. when
efficiency is the name of the game. The
number one thing I I I'm telling you
right now in 2025 and going into 2026 is
the people who are going to dominate
in the space of online sales and online
marketing,
they have the ability to
have the shortest amount of time between
the ideas they have and executing and
getting that stuff out there to people.
And they are using artificial
intelligence to be able to do so. Right
now I'm studying different platforms and
ways of using AI even to create content.
This is not an AI generated video at
all. But at the same time, if I take
certain videos that I have, having an AI
that could generate certain content for
me and clips and things like that,
there's actually a benefit to that and
being able to put all of that together
to save me time so that I can make
content and reach people with my message
without having to be on all the time to
come up with it.
living a relaxed lifestyle, living a
lifestyle where I can spend time with my
kids.
I can spend a couple hours with them in
the middle of the morning, in the
afternoon, right before I recorded this
video, in fact. And I know that it's
actually not going to negatively affect
my business, that I don't need to grind
all day, and that I can show up and
record content that flows from a state
of being authentic. and it's it's 100%
me and what I want to share with people
and I know that the topic that I'm
sharing is going to really affect
people. So that's the thing is
shortening the amount of time that you
come up with and take the content.
You're going to shorten the amount of
time that it takes you to come up with
ideas.
Okay, since it's stage one ideiation,
this is where we can use AI to help us
with this. This is also where one of the
things that I like to do is I'll come up
with a couple of different ideas with
the AI. I don't go B ever based off of
like what the AI just says. I will then
kind of sit with it for a little bit and
process through how it feels and then it
will trigger my brain. See, I'm using
the AI to trigger my brain. So, it's AI
plus experience
to really come up with what people need
to hear from me. Okay? And this is just
an overarching idea. Then what I will do
as I go from ideiation to
decision.
Okay? Making a decision as far as what I
am going to teach. I decide
what it is that I'm going to be sharing.
Whether it be AI content, whether it be
an email that I'm going to be sending
out to people, whether it be some piece
of content that I'm creating, whether it
be a YouTube video or Instagram short.
And then we take action.
So it's idea,
not aida, ada, attention, interest,
desire, action. It's ideiation,
decision, action. And the idea behind
this is that if we can shorten the
amount of time that each of these steps
takes to as little as possible with no
lag time
to where you're not delaying, to where
you're not procrastinating in these
ways, you will set yourself apart and be
so far ahead of everybody else in your
industry, all of the coaches that are
out there. The reason why most coaches
and mentors right now today are
struggling to get clients is because
they are taking way too long to make
decisions in their life. They're taking
way too long to decide which ideas
they're going to take action on. And
then to go from once they make a
decision to finally taking action. And
learning to shorten that length of time
is truly a superpower and a skill. And
it's something that you can learn. And
it's something that I mentor my clients
in all the time. And one of the biggest
things is this is that often times we
are so emotionally charged. Our brain is
so focused on so many different things.
We have so many things going on in our
life that we have to do is we have to
put blinders on and we have to have deep
focus on what is the one single task at
hand that I'm going to set out to do.
What is that one task at hand that I'm
going to set out to do to get results
on? And when we do this, we're not
thinking about all this different stuff.
I will often get out of my mind what
anybody thinks about the content that
I'm creating. I completely just imagine
that I'm talking to somebody who's just
like loves everything that I create.
They just think that all of my like like
there's a hypothetical client that's out
there that just like everything that I
talk about is the best thing that they
could imagine. So what I do is I just
imagine that whatever I'm making, that's
the person who's listening to it. that
that right now who I'm talking to is
somebody who just absolutely loves my
content. I visualize somebody loving
what I'm sharing. And then that gets me
out of the state of expectation of
people disliking it. What's somebody
going to think or all this negativity
that I don't even want to entertain that
negativity anymore? I don't even want to
think about that. I don't even let it
enter into my mind anymore. And this is
something that took me a long time to do
where I no longer let the thoughts,
feelings, and opinions of people that
dislike me or disagree with me affect
any of the decisions and choices that
I'm making. And I also don't allow my
spirit of excellence to be a self-critic
that causes me to not take action
quickly. that causes me to be so focused
on doing things right and perfect that I
delay doing the things that are actually
going to be successful for me. When you
can train your brain to do this, you
will be far more successful in your
business than you ever possibly imagine
because you can get out your marketing
campaigns, your lead magnets, your
webinars. You can launch your
advertising campaigns. You can reach
more people. You can then get one of
those done and you can iterate and
create another one. You'll make a
decision on joining a coaching program
instead of waffling around and wondering
is this the right program for me? And
you'll be able to then decide, okay,
these are the actions to take in my
business that no matter what I'm feeling
today, come come
hell or high water, it's okay. I'm going
to take action today and I'm going to do
the stuff that I know is going to get
the best result for me. oftentimes we
can't predict exactly what results are
going to happen, but we know that if we
can control the input,
we can get a lot more output out of it.
And oftentimes we're controlling the
wrong input. We're trying to curate the
quality of the input. We're trying to
make sure that the input is the perfect
piece of input when in fact I believe
it's more based on the volume and
frequency and consistency of the input.
that the more frequent and the more
consistent that you put inputs into your
business, that is going to scale and
that's going to actually produce better
results by then shortening the amount of
energy and time that it takes for you to
actually put those things into place.
Once you get this, you will start to see
the effects and the results of it when
it becomes a lifestyle for you. Not just
a single moment in time, not just
something that you're just going to do
once, but something that you do
consistently over and over and over
again.
You know, I've had to learn how to do
this a whole new way now that I have two
kids. It's different than it was when I
had no kids. It's different than it was
with one child. But now I realize, you
know what? What's going to produce the
results for me in my business is
learning how to take quick action on the
ideas I have to get the results that I
want. And I'm not trying to control them
by curating everything perfectly.
Rather, I want to be prolific
and effective in my business. Slightly
reckless in what I'm putting out there,
but it's planned out based on I know
that this topic is going to help people.
And I'm not overthinking it. I'm not
overanalyzing it. I'm not letting the
overanalysis create paralysis or
temporary paralysis.
I'm taking action because I know that
doing something right now, recording
this video is better than me sitting
around trying to come up with the right
way to say the things that I want to
say. All right? And this will work for
you. I'd love to see you in my Wealthy
Coach Academy program. You can try it
out for 14 days. Go check out the link
below. Check out how you can get in
there. We'll talk soon. Have a good one.